Ahmed Darwish Senior Android Engineer (Android & KMM)

ahmed.darwish.dev@gmail.com

+201112321940

Egypt, Cairo

in www.linkedin.com/in/eng-ahmed-darwish

https://github.com/darwish1994

Profile

I'm an Android developer with solid knowledge and 6 years of field experience in the design, implementation,

and maintenance of software solutions. Familiar with SDLC methodologies like Agile-Scrum, as well as a variety

of design patterns, used in combination with solid coding techniques to deliver a robust, maintainable product.

Focused on mobile native programming using object-oriented Kotlin and Java, as well as technologies and tools

like Coroutines, Koin, Dagger-Hilt, Room, Firebase, Retrofit, Mockito, Jenkins, SonarQube, Git, Jira, Confluence

Professional Experience

2019/02 - present

Senior Android Engineer (Android & KMM)

Cairo, Maadi, Egypt Awfar.inc 🗷

Developed and maintained mobile applications, Implemented new features and functionality for Android applications, Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop mobile applications that met business requirements, Integrated Restful APIs and third-party libraries to enhance the application

functionality

2021/02 - 2021/06

Senior Android developer

Cairo, City center,

DigitalYard 🛮

Egypt

Developed native Android applications and frameworks, Defined and implemented robust app architectures and complex user interfaces, Collaborated with designers, engineers, and product managers to build great experiences and develop Cisco

communication plugins using Java.

2018/01 - 2019/02

Android Developer

Giza, Egypt

Log-Apps

Developed native Android applications and frameworks, developed an SDK for remote control, got requirements from

clients and Developed a web application

Education

2012/10 – 2016/06 Hellwan, Egypt **BACALOR'S OF COMPUTER SCIENCE**

pt FCIH, Hellwan univercity

Certificates

Android Development By Google ☑

Languages

• English

Arabic

Skills

kotlin	• • • •	java	••••
KMM	• • • •	Kotlin coroutines	• • • • •
Concurrency and Multithreading	• • • •	Reactive programing (Rxjava and kotlin flow)	• • • • •
Realem/Room database	• • • • •		
Dependency Injections	••••	Restful APIs	••••
(Dagger2,Hilt,Koin)		Android Jetpack	••••
Unit testing and UI tests	• • • •	Compose UI	••••
XML	• • • •	Architecture Pattern (MVVM, MVI)	••••
Git	• • • •	CI/CD	••••
Google Services	• • • •	Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM)	• • • • •
Understand the app signing process	• • • •	Publish your app on the Google Play Store	• • • • •
Hardware integration (NFC, WIFI, BLUTOOTH)	• • • •		

Projects

Elezaby Pharmacy 🛮

E-commerce

Ezaby is an Egyptian healthcare platform that offers various services to users, including telemedicine consultations, pharmacy deliveries, and access to medical professionals. Through the Ezaby app, users can conveniently schedule virtual appointments with doctors, order medications for home delivery, and access healthcare information and resources. It aims to provide accessible and convenient healthcare solutions to individuals in Egypt

Awfar Connect 🛮

Delievery App

Delivery management app is a software as a service, which communicates the order cycle, starting from collecting orders and delivering them to the end user.

Scholigit parent

E-Learing

Mobile app to solve school/nursery and parent impacts and negotiations and ease interactions between school or nursery, teachers, and parents by connecting all parties on a unified platform that helps school, nursery, and parents to reach each other easily and efficiently.

Awfar Chat

Chat Service

app helps companies create support channels over popular social media. like facebook,WhatsApp and etc..

وياك - Wayak

Medication App

App for Medical Society, helps patients to get their medicine rapidly before it finishes

Maktabt Hamdy 🛮

Stationary App

stationary app, selling different types of products.

Medi Go 🛮

X-ray booking service The Medical Service App helps the user book health services like x-rays.

Tebcom ☑

Medical video sessions A medical app where users book sessions with other doctors and get video calls or chat sessions